It is now undeniable that the
"Arab Spring" has turned into "Arab Winter".
Egypt's issue is not about democracy or autocracy,
but whether the country is being misgoverned or not.
We will be easily influenced by an idealized illusion
if we cannot realize the significance of political life.
How significant is the impact of the "Arab Spring"
on the EU and Europe?
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 微信公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
For Chinese people, Egypt is most recognized for its tourism.
However, after the "Arab Spring",
many organizations, including the Chinese Embassy,
constantly issue warning to Chinese tourists
to prioritise safety.
At many scenic spots, there are
soldiers carrying loaded weapons to ensure security.
The western countries promised to bring the light of
freedom and democracy to Arab World.
However, their first move resulted in
turbulence in Egypt, even until now.
The so-called "Arab Spring" happened in 2011.
I was acquainted to an
Egyptian reporter in 2012 or 2013.
We asked him about the situtation in Egypt
one or two years after the "Arab Spring".
He was pitiful saying that Egypt used to be very safe,
especially in Cairo, the capital city,
when Chinese tourists visited.
But now, you are very likely to face various levels of harassment
if you are a woman walking on the street in Cairo,
which is not safe at all.
This is the observation by an Egyptian reporter.
So the issue is:
why did the hope and aspiration the people held
turn into the situation described by you two?
There must be a complicated reason behind it.
I think Professor Zhang could help us analyze the reasons.
We roughly know what they are.
For example, the cure they craved for.
was a packaged solution imported from the west:
politics - implementing a multi-party system,
and an electoral system right away.
Are these good solutions ?
More than eight years has passed,
The situations of many countries and regions,
not just Egypt,
like Libya, Yemen, Tunisia and so forth,
are even worse than
before the color revolutions took place.
Now we only see the destruction, not the construction.
Where's the construction?
The western countries need to provide an answer
as they instigated and overturned
so many governments.
Was there any country which improved a lot
and reached the "perfect world on
the other shore" as promised?
Probably none.
More importantly, after their
governments were overturned,
it was the people who were
bearing the consequences.
This is a critical issue.
Egypt's economy was doing alright
among Northern African countries.
However, since Hosni Mubarak stepped down,
the economy is worsening.
Based on my personal observation
and interviewing experience,
for example, I lived in Tibet for seven months,
filming a documentary.
I found Tibet has its own
unique natural environment, and ethnic culture.
For regions which are struggling economically,
I believe having policies from the central
government is of vital importance.
Many economic policies and systematic
reform, should consider
how moderate they are, how quickly they are
implemented, as well as their scope and depth.
If they are implemented in a haste, or if they
came out of nowhere,
or forced to be adopted,
new disasters and unrest are likely to occur.
So I hope that Professor Zhang can elaborate on this
to our audience.
Is one regions' package solution suitable for another?
Is it good medicine or bad drugs with
tremendous side effects?
For many politicians, this question is worth considering.
What kind of governance is suitable for
the culture and history of this place?
Chinese people always say: "seek truth from the facts" and "adapt to local conditions."
And "acclimatize to the local water and soil"
These points are significant. We may run into some
economic difficulties, or some other issues,
and it's vital what prescription you choose
to solve the problem.
It tests a government on its
overall governance capacities
I think this point can absolutely be drawn from the transition from the "Arab Spring" to the "Arab Winter".
Hello everyone,
welcome to China Now.
We are here to position China, learn about China, and understand China.
Standing next to me are our two guests,
our keynote speaker, Prof. Zhang Weiwei, Director of
the China Institute of Fudan University,
and also Prof. Fan Yongpeng, Associate Director
of the China Institute of Fudan University.
Our two guests will hold a discussion with us.
But let's first listen to the keynote speech
from Professor Zhang.
Welcome!
It is now undeniable that the "Arab Spring"
has become "Arab Winter".
We need to understand the reason of the change,
because it's crucial for us to establish
confidence in our own political path.
You all probably know that the "Arab Spring" began
with a vendor burning himself in Tunisia
towards the end of 2010.
It sparked dissatisfactions among
the Tunisian people
about unemployment, inflation, and corruption,
which further led to the unrest.
However, Tunisia is just a small country
with a population of tens of millions.
The “Arab Spring” quickly spread to a big Middle Eastern country, Egypt,
with a population of nearly a hundred million.
Suddenly everyone felt the severity of the situation.
Then "Arab Spring" expanded to many countries in Western Asia, and Northern Africa.
Back then, western countries cheered,
claiming a new Middle East would be born.
However, eight years later,
Libya has broken apart
and the whole country fell into anarchy and civil war.
Even the American ambassador was killed.
Tunisia did not disintegrate but its economy has been hit hard.
The original secular regime has become an
increasingly Islamic one.
Yemen is also in turmoil.
The country with a population of 23 million,
less than that of Shanghai,
is having three wars simultaneously,
a war among tribes, a war among sects,
and a war between the government army and Al-Qaeda,
Maybe, southern Yemen will also start a
war demanding independence.
Furthermore Syria, which enjoyed relative prosperity,
turned into a hell on earth.
The current Egyptian President Al-Sisi said,
what happened in Syria, Iraq, Libya, and Yemen
caused huge losses to life and property.
Damage to infrastructure reached up to
900 billion dollars.
The death toll exceeded 1.4 million, and 150 million
people became refugees.
This is what I refer to as a sin.
I have been to these Middle Eastern countries,
like Tunisia, and Syria,
but I have only been there once.
However, I have been to Egypt 6 or 7 times.
So I can expand on
how the "Arab Spring" transitioned to an "Arab Winter".
In January 2011,
a massive wave of anti-government protest
emerged in Cairo, Egypt.
In February 11, the long-term Egyptian President
Hosni Mubarak stepped down.
Back then, the western media were very excited,
claiming the great western democracy finally arrived in the Arab world, in Egypt.
I have conducted many investigations
in the Middle East and Egypt.
I also lived together with ordinary Egyptian people.
So I know the situation quite well.
Eight years ago, when I debated with Francis Fukuyama,
I accurately predicted that the "Arab Spring"
would turn into an "Arab Winter".
The Chinese people emphasize
"the unity between perception and action"
We also say "Read ten thousand books and
walk ten thousand miles".
Deng Xiaoping, once said,
"A soldier who has heard gunfire is completely different
from to the one who has not."
To be there and investigate makes a difference
than when one does not.
I believe that doing research,
especially political science,
should have a sense of politics, and be hands-on,
otherwise you cannot understand
neither China's nor the world's politics.
In Egypt, I once flew from North to South,
from the capital Cairo to Aswan
along the Nile River.
Looking around,
on both sides of the Nile River, beyond a long and narrow oasis,
there is an endless desert.
At that point, you realize the value of Nile River
for the existence of Egypt: it is Egypt's lifeline.
Egypt’s natural environment is very harsh:
the country is around one million
square kilometers in size,
with 95% of it being desert.
In 2011, its population was nearly 90 million,
but they all lived on 5% of its territory.
Therefore, the resources per capita were extremely limited.
Nevertheless, its population
increased rapidly and was very young,
as 50% were less than 25 years old.
But there was no decent manufacturing industry.
This meant high unemployment rate
among youngsters - greater than 30%.
There were idle young people everywhere in the Egyptian streets.
If you go to countries which have gone through the
"Arab Spring", like Tunisia, Syria, and Algeria,
you will find the situations are alike.
Unemployed young people
became the main participants of the "Arab Spring".
In 2008 when the Financial Crisis broke out,
the U.S. heavily engaged in quantitative easing.
In reality, they were transferring the danger.
This led to an overall increase in prices
in the Middle East, including Egypt.
The Egyptian currency, the Egyptian Pound,
depreciated quickly.
The prices of staple foods for Egyptian people,
such as bread, tomato, beef and mutton,
multiplied.
When I was in Egypt,
my students accompanied me for a field trips
at produce markets in Cairo.
The price of one kilogram of tomatoes increased
six-fold within half a year,
from 2 Egyptian pounds to 12 Egyptian pounds,
which is around 2 dollars for one kilogram.
Back then, 40% of the Egyptian people
earned less than 2 dollars a day.
Life was really hard.
This is all because of its unhealthy economic structure.
It was misformed.
Overall, Egypt is impoverished,
with a huge gap between the rich and the poor.
The national economy heavily depends on
imported consumer goods,
resulting in colossal national debts.
I followed our former president Li Xiannian
when I first visited Egypt in 1986.
One of the important issues they discussed was that
Egypt requested to delay debt repayment to China
because of economic difficulties.
Egypt imported 9 billion USD of
consumer goods a year
while foreign exchange income was just
7 billion USD.
Mubarak had been in power for over 30 years.
He instituted reforms and conducted
structural adjustment to the economy,
but he still failed to generate a strong manufacturing
industry for enough employment opportunities .
So Egypt relied on the import
of crops and many daily necessities.
As the economy worsened,
corruption became more severe.
Rumors were everywhere about
corrupt senior government officials,
especially Mubarak's family.
People thought his family illegally owned
over ten billion U.S. dollars overseas.
Although, in the end, there was no proof,
these rumors jeopardized Mubarak's prestige in Egypt.
Since it used to be the colony of the UK and France,
Egypt inherited many traditions during the colonial times.
The senior government officials in Egypt
mostly completed their education in Europe or America.
They are out of touch with their people.
This leads to low governance competence.
In 1987, I followed Deputy Prime Minister, Li Peng
to visit the Aswan Dam
[the world's largest embankment dam]
We were accompanied by the
Deputy Minister of Electricity.
He accompanied us the whole time.
He studied in the U.K. and spoke English fluently.
Deputy Prime Minister, Li Peng asked him
the price of one kilowatt-hour of electricity.
The Deputy Minster didn't know and
asked his subordinate.
His subordinate had no clue either and
asked another person.
In the end, they provided an answer.
Li Peng sighed, telling me that
they were very bureaucratic,
but not to translate this [back to the Egyptians].
Actually, this situation is ubiquitous
in developing countries.
The upper-class elites are born rich,
educated in western countries,
but severely disconnected from their own society.
They are very bureaucratic and ignorant
of their people's misery.
They don't have the same tradition
as in the Chinese political culture
"A term served is a region benefited."
I would also like to take this opportunity
to extend my condolence for the
passing of Comrade Li Peng,
as I accompanied him to visit multiple countries in the 1980s.
I can share another memory with you.
In July 1985, I accompanied him to visit the United States.
We visited a famous think tank called RAND Corporation.
Li Peng made a joke and asked the researchers
that China proposed to quadruple our GDP
by the end of this century,
which is to say,
to increase four times compared to that of 1980.
Li Peng asked them by how much we should
increase the output of electricity
if we wanted to achieve that goal.
They said they hadn't researched this problem
but they can do the project for the Chinese government.
Li Peng laughed and thanked them, saying that we
already have conducted the research.
After leaving the RAND Corporation, Li Peng
said to us that Comrade Xiaoping
was the first person to raise this concern.
He asked Li Peng directly,
who was in charge of China's electricity.
Deng Xiaoping asked,
by how much do we have to increase our electrical
output, to ensure that the economy quadruples?
Then Li Peng started the research,
and raised a ambitious, but also attainable goal.
Do you know the total power generation capacity
of entire China in one year?
It was seven trillion kilowatt-hours in 2018,
almost the total of combined power generation
of the seven major industrial countries
also over 1000 times of total power generation in 1949.
So today, in a vast country,
in such a scorching summer,
we all use air conditioning, but we don't lack electricity.
When the heat wave hit,
New York had two power outages,
and train stations in Paris also
experienced power outages.
"Never forget the well digger when drinking water."
Under the lead of Deng Xiaoping,
Deputy Prime Minister Li Peng
was in charge of electricity, industry, and education.
He devoted himself to his work.
I one of the witnesses of the developments
in our electrical industry.
What may comfort Li Peng is,
China is now the country with the most abundant power
generation supply in the world,
and it is also the brightest country in the world at night.
Sometimes I even don't want to add "one of".
We want to pay tribute to all electricity workers in China.
You are the best in the world.
Let's get back to Egypt.
Due to internal and external reasons,
the life quality in Egypt didn't improve
and various social contradictions
are becoming increasingly acute.
The whole society is like being covered with dry wood,
and only a little spark will make it burn and explode.
The small vendor burning himself
became the little spark,
triggering this turmoil and revolution.
Revolution is romantic, but the issues
afterwards are complicated and severe.
Lots of deep-rooted issues are unsolvable.
From my own experience of field trips,
as long as Arab countries really implement
universal suffrage, "one person one vote",
Islamic forces, rather than
Pro-Western liberal forces will come into power.
In the presidential election following the "Arab Spring",
Mohamed Morsi, from the Muslim Brotherhood,
came to power as expected.
Then Egypt started struggling over Secular versus Islamic.
Electoral politics deepened the conflicts
between the two major factions -
both refused to compromise,
leading to the country's chaos,
capital flights, bankruptcies, and
soaring prices and crime rates.
Finally in July 2013, the army removed
the elected President Morsi from office,
of course resulting in some new turmoil.
When Westerners celebrated the "Arab Spring",
many Egyptians were happy too.
They believed all their issues could be solved by
adopting a model resembling western democracy.
However, this example tells us that the Egypt's problem
was not about democracy or autocracy,
but whether the country was well governed or not.
If the issue was about democracy or autocracy,
then Egypt could have solved all problems
by copying the western democratic model.
But in fact, the entrenched problems I mentioned earlier,
such as population explosion, destitution,
and economic structure -
not a single one of them can be resolved
by the western model.
On the contrary, the western model can
even exacerbate those problems.
This is a direct reason that the "Arab Spring"
rapidly turned into the "Arab Winter".
I think the Chinese idiom from our ancestors
"not acclimatized to the local water and soil"
can explain it very well.
They are really full of wisdom.
I looked up the idiom's origin - it was first used in
The Biography of Zhou Yu, Records of the Three Kingdoms
"You will get sick if you are not accustomed to the water and soil.”
The use of these two words
"water and soil' is very accurate.
This can be a part of China's native political discourse.
Any country and society is comprised of at least four pillars -
politics, economy, society, and culture.
Culture is fundamental, as it permeates everywhere.
So when we talk about "not acclimatized the local water and soil",
water refers to culture, permeating everywhere,
and the soil is the political soil,
the economic soil, and the societal soil.
The Western political model failed to "acclimatize to the local water and soil" in Arab world.
Let's talk about water first - the culture.
Egypt is deeply influenced by Islamic culture.
Mosques. Minarets.
Praying five times a day; never-ending prayers.
Although there are secular sects,
the influence of Islam is far greater than that of
secular sects at the bottom of society.
From the perspective of political culture,
irreconcilable contradictions exist between
Islamic forces and secular forces.
The contradictions are long-standing.
As soon as one party gains power,
it aims to eliminate the other.
When the other party regains power,
they purge and avenge.
Therefore, their political culture and tradition lacks
compromise and tolerance.
When they adopted the Western electoral process,
they continuously deepened their
discrepancies, intensified conflicts,
and further tore apart their society.
Let's take a look at the political soil.
There are three political forces inside Egypt,
the Islamist, the secular, and the army.
The Islamist and the secular have been
at odds for a long time.
The main difference is about what kind
of a country should be built.
The Islamists advocate the establishment of a Caliphate. [Islamic state under the leadership of a steward]
They think Egypt has been on the wrong
path for hundreds of years.
That has to come to an end.
The "Arab Spring" gave them a chance.
In the same way, the secularists want to
establish a secular state,
not allowing the country to go back to
becoming a Caliphate.
Now let's look at the economic soil.
The Egyptian economy had four pillars:
tourism, income from Suez Canal, overseas remittance,
which is the money sent back from
overseas Egyptians, and petroleum.
As I have mentioned before,
the economic structure lacked
manufacturing and real economy.
For a big Middle Eastern country with
a population close to 100 million people,
this economic structure couldn't generate enough jobs.
Therefore, there was high youth unemployment.
This led to a situation
where if there was no political pressure and Mubarak's regime,
young people would come to the street.
Street politics would cause more unrest and even violence.
Therefore, "Arab Spring" brought unrest,
bankruptcies, and capital flights.
The issue of livelihood was not only
one major reason to cause "Arab Spring",
but also a major factor deepening
Egyptian political turmoil.
Then let's look at the societal soil.
With the rise of the Internet and the worsening of economy,
external forces including the U.S.
actively promoted the "color revolution".
Social trends were becoming increasingly extreme.
We could see in the news,
even from mainstream foreign media,
and also the domestic media,
that the "Arab Spring" is a
"Three-No's" political movement.
No clear guiding principle, no coherent organization,
and no iconic leaders.
However, this is not true.
In 2012, a monograph on the
Arab revolution was published in France,
« La Face Cachee des Revolutions Arabes »
This book was co-authored by 23 scholars from
eight countries, including France, Belgium,
Algeria, and Tunisia, etc.
This book raises the view that
the U.S. pushed behind the Arab Spring.
It details how the U.S. facilitated the Arab Spring
through training their key activists,
and by using the Internet.
Some so-called NGOs and foundations
were deeply engaged in this street revolution.
This book also lists some
famous American organizations,
which we all may know,
National Endowment for Democracy,
and Freedom House,
United States Agency for International Development,
and Open Society Institute, etc.
Actually, we can also see their shadows
during the color revolution in
Eastern Europe and the Soviet Union.
Some of them manipulated behind the scenes.
This book also discloses that
from 2002, way before thte "Arab Spring" broke out,
those organizations started
planning the Arab Revolution.
In the 5 years from 2005 to 2010,
they trained at least 10,000
Internet experts in Egypt,
which cost them 20 million dollars yearly
and the number doubled later.
Because of this,
in 2012, some Egyptian organizations
accused some of them of
illegally raising funds.
However, the U.S. State Department objected it.
So we can see U.S. citizens were
engaged in these activities.
This book also reaches the conclusion
that intervention by the U.S. took place on two levels:
the first is cyberspace, and the second is training activists.
So they trained a multitude of
Internet experts or influencers,
whose mother tongue are Arabic.
They formed the so-called Internet Arab Association,
and set up topics on the Internet.
They were "summoning winds and calling for rain".
According to Gene Sharp [American political scientist],
these organizations systematically
trained the backbone of street politics.
These methods used during the color revolution
are ubiquitous in recent anti-extradition riots in Hong Kong
from the signs and outfits of the demonstrators,
to the gestures used by their supervisors.
It is obvious that American color revolution experts
trained these demonstrators.
Not a long time ago, a video circulated on the Internet
that in a university speech, the current
U.S. Secretary of State, Mike Pompeo
publicly acknowledged that
when he was the Director of the CIA.
"We lied, deceived, and stole.
We had entire training courses."
"It reminds you of the glory of the American experiment."
He is proud of it.
Actually, American extremist forces
provide us with new lessons every day,
which also slap some Chinese
public intellectuals in the face every day.
Chinese people are getting to know the truth behind
the color revolution and their orchestrators.
People interested in politics may have noticed that
western mainstream media did their utmost to control
public opinion after the "Arab Spring".
They depicted the movement as a
spontaneous revolution of the masses
and they attacked all media and scholars raising
different opinions as conspiracy theorists.
The western media intentionally portrayed
anti-government organizations as heroes
and the government as a butcher.
From what happened in Hong Kong,
we saw clearly how the so-called "western free press"
complied with the color revolution routine.
If there's any difference between Hong Kong and Egypt,
I assume that would be the U.S. exerted
a larger and deeper involvement in Hong Kong.
Even though Hong Kong has less than
one tenth of the population of Egypt.
We have to raise a question here:
Why did America target Egypt's former president Mubarak?
Mubarak had been regarded as America's
faithful friend for many years?
Just now I introduced a Chinese concept -
"not acclimatize to the local water and soil" to analyze why the "Arab Spring" turned into the "Arab Winter".
Now I am introducing an English concept, "deep state"
to explain why the U.S. would overturn
their old friend, Mubarak.
The deep state refers to "a state behind the state".
A deep-level contact network that really influences America's state behavior,
like its military-industrial complex, capital from Wall Street,
the CIA, and National Endowment for Democracy, etc.
So the American presidents come and go -
some are friendly and some are not,
but the position of the deep state is always consistent.
They have been committed to overthrowing the systems
which are different from theirs in a
planned and premeditated manner.
Not only against China, but also against other countries.
As long as you have a different political system,
they would support your enemy, train proxies,
and the fifth column.
For China, they support Xinjiang independence, Tibet independence, Taiwan independence,
Hong Kong independence, and people
with different political opinions.
What kind of benefits would they get from this?
First, they let their proxy, who represents
their interests, take over the government,
making the country a vassal of America.
At that time, Mubarak was not close enough to U.S.,
he was still independent.
And Wall Street always supports the so-called democratization.
Once a proxy appears,
they will support the political party it becomes.
Democracy is only realized if that
favored party is elected,
otherwise it is a faux democracy.
Wall Street is behind that favored party, which wants to
rob the country and its people of their wealth.
It doesn't matter if this objective is not fully achieved
because at least they can disarray a country or a region,
ideally leading to an internal war.
Then the military-industrial complex of thte U.S.
can sell its weapons
for the parties to fight each other.
Back in the 1950s,
American president Dwight D. Eisenhower
requested that the American society
be weary of the American military-industrial complex
abducting the American political system.
However, as it stands currently, the
abduction is getting worse,
which is also the root cause of many
problems in the U.S.
and many upheavals around the world.
From the analysis above,
I want to help all of you understand from a Chinese perspective
what the "Arab Spring" is, why the U.S. backed it,
and why the "Arab Spring" must become "Arab Winter".
Knowing all this, we can avoid being deceived,
and resolutely follow the successful path
explored by the our predecessors.
We can annihilate any color revolution
staged by America and its proxies
so that the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation
will become easier and smoother.
That's all for today.
Thanks everyone.
Thank you Professor Zhang for your speech.
He told us how the "Arab Spring" turned
into the "Arab Winter".
There may be some objective reasons in the countries
where color revolutions broke out.
In addition, are there forces behind to
propel those color revolutions?
When economic and social issues arise in one place,
can they be resolved by measures
native to local dynamics,
or by cutting corners to use measures directly copied
from western societies?
Is there a panacea for all the problems?
I think Professor Zhang presented his opinions.
Next let's hear your opinions through our Q&A session.
Before we start our conversation,
I would like to invite Professor Fan
to share his thoughts.
To understand the "Arab Spring", we need to put it
into an international political context.
During the Cold War, the U.S. used those dictatorships
to compete with the Soviet Union.
After the disintegration of Soviet Union, those dictatorships weren't obedient to the U.S.
when they didn't need help from it.
Therefore, the U.S. needed to eliminate them.
At the same time, as it had no competitors
on the international stage,
the U.S. wanted a low-cost approach,
which is representative democracy.
Representative democracy can easily
be manipulated by external forces.
It has been very successful, such as
the third wave of democratization,
including the color revolutions in Soviet Union,
Eastern Europe and Middle Asia,
followed by "Arab Spring".
At this moment, as was explained by Professor Zhang,
some issues came up in America internally.
The interests of different capital groups began to differ.
The deep state, or the powers of the
financial industry and the military-industrial complex,
overrode the interest of the country.
A former U.S. Ambassador to Saudi Arabia,
Charles Freeman, who later served in China,
said America totally forgot its strategic
goals after the 2003 Iraq War.
Think about it: from the Iraq War, Afghanistan War,
to the "Arab Spring",
the U.S. didn't benefit from them.
What's the result ?
In Middle East, the enemy of America's enemy
is still America's enemy.
Ultimately, only Wall Street, the military-industrial complex, and Big Oil benefited.
This is a small group in the country.
Therefore, placed into this context,
the people in Arab countries are miserable.
I am inspired by two things Professor Zhang mentioned.
One is Professor Zhang's quotation
of what Deng Xiaoping said,
"The soldiers who heard the gunfire
are different than those who did not."
Actually it can be extended that
it makes a difference for us ordinary people
whether you have heard the gunfire
and experienced wars and chaos.
My generation as well as some youngsters
here in the audience
may be influenced by some western ideologies -
thinking we can solve many problems by
calling for rights and starting social movements.
However, Sun Tzu once said,
[Chinese strategist around 500BC]
"Warfare concerns the lives of the people
and the survival of a country."
So does politics. Politics can also cause people to die.
We will be easily influenced by an idealized illusion
if we cannot realize the significance of political life.
This can bring serious consequences.
This is an important inspiration.
The second insight,
mentioned by Professor Zhang,
is the disjointedness between the
Egyptian elites and Egyptian people.
I will also share a story.
Three years ago, when the Mombasa-Nairobi Railway built by China was completed in Kenya,
I attended the opening ceremony,
and I ate and exchanged ideas with
local lawyers and the news media.
They opposed the Mombasa-Nairobi Railway strongly.
We were eating very good seafood.
And I said the Mombasa-Nairobi Railway
can transport great seafood from Mombasa to Nairobi,
which can be enjoyed by the locals.
Then the lawyer made my jaw drop,
asking me "Why should locals eat this?"
This is what I heard.
So I realized in those countries, these elites and some compradors -
they were educated well in the West,
but not interested in their country.
Their interests are aligned with international capital groups.
Hence, the two points are meaningful for
young generations to comprehend the "Arab Spring"
Just now the two professors said that
politics is not a dinner party, but bleeding and sacrifice.
They also talked about the manipulation and
intervention of western media in Hong Kong recently.
You can see the local media and western media swarmed to condemn the police,
fanning hatred, and calming one side to provoke the other.
This is a living example.
Our conversation will now begin.
Yes, please. Welcome.
Some people say the "Arab Spring" put the EU
on the brink of disintegration.
How much influence did it exert on Europe and EU ?
Please sit down.
The impact of this revolution on Europe.
It had huge negative repercussions
on European politics.
The most difficult problem in Europe is the
refugee issue - refugees from the Middle East.
Over 1 million refugees flocked into Europe,
and several million refugees are on their way.
Europe really had a headache.
On one hand, EU has already split up.
Those countries that supported the "Arab Spring" in the name of human rights and humanitarian intervention,
like the U.K. and France,
are the least willing to accept refugees.
Central and Eastern European countries
refused to implement the
Common European Asylum System.
The EU wants to distribute refugees
proportionally to every country.
But almost all Central and Eastern European countries
refused to accept a single refugee,
even Denmark refused now.
Other countries, like Greece, asked for money
to perform some temporary work
and build "a frontline of defense".
So the EU has actually already split up.
Inside the European countries,
right-wing forces are visibly on the rise.
This is actually happening in most countries.
But from my perspective,
the EU will not disintegrate because of this.
The EU, with its huge market and unified currency,
still plays a major role
and offers opportunities for young people.
However, the overall prospect is becoming
dimmer than before.
I remember that I said before, that in 30 years
China’s economic scale should be
a combination of the United States
and the EU, if the EU still exists.
Professor Zhang just said that Central
and Eastern European countries are not enthusiastic.
Why is this the case?
It is because Central and Eastern European countries are
farther away from Mediterranean.
People normally travel through Greece, Italy or Spain from the Middle East.
Central and Eastern European countries asked for more
money to fund protective measures.
So there are divisions inside Europe.
Let me make an analogy.
If we say Europe is a pot,
the Arabian Mediterranean area is the stove underneath.
They are closely connected.
Historically, Europeans were very afraid that
the turmoil in the eastern and southern Mediterranean would "burn towards" the Europeans.
This explains why the U.S.-Europe relations
were good up to 2003
but France and Germany literally broke up with America
on the Iraq War in 2003.
Why? The U.S. is like a spoiled child, throwing an
ink bottle at the pillow side of Europe
and thus splashing ink onto Europe.
So Europeans were upset.
Then came a turning point.
Historically, all French governments were independent
and they maintained order in the Mediterranean.
However, after [French President] Nicolas Sarkozy came in power,
he followed the U.S. for his own political interests.
So he acted as a vanguard
in intervening Libya and the Mediterranean.
This led to the political collapse of the Mediterranean
and also impacted Europe's security and order.
Several years ago I attended a conference
about the refugee crisis, which was
organized by a German.
I had only one point - this conference was not necessary.
The only thing you should do is to go
back to the Mediterranean,
including Syria and Libya, to restore political order.
All problems will be solved.
As long as the local life is back in order,
people will not leave.
- They all miss home.
- Yes, who likes leaving their home?
Let's see if anyone in the audience here
would like to ask a question.
Yes, please.
The "Arab Spring" is a movement to pursue
equality and democracy in Arab world.
It well demonstrated that people around the world
long for equality and democracy.
My question is: what is the root cause
of the "Arab Winter"?
Sure, please be seated.
His first point is very interesting.
He thinks it's indeed a movement
for local people to pursue democracy.
What is your opinion?
The demands by Arabs for jobs, equality,
a better life, and dignity,
are acceptable and understandable.
However, political activities cannot go too far.
Specifically, when you are pursuing this goal,
you need to know what your actions can result in.
To what extent should you stop?
Should you overturn the existing political system?
Is this helpful to your goal?
You need political wisdom to think it through.
Besides, methods and means should also be considered.
Western countries hold double standards about this.
A lot of rules can be found regarding the right of free speech and freedom of assembly in the U.S.,
for example,
during the assembly, you cannot affect traffic.
Otherwise, you will be arrested.
Whether it's Wall Street, New York, or Washington,
all demonstrators will return to the curb
when the police come.
The rules are clear.
However, the west doesn't say so about Hong Kong.
Here is the trick.
When you voice your opinions and reasonable demands,
be aware of being manipulated by others.
I want to add a point, from Samuel Phillips Huntington,
[American political scientist]
which I think it's defensible.
Have you noticed the real problems
of the "Arab Spring" and the color revolution?
It's called political participation explosion.
Huntington pointed out
political participation is one factor
and institution building is another.
If the two are not at the same level,
for example, if political participation is high
and institution building is low,
it leads to unrest, revolution, and chaos.
That's the biggest problem.
The two factors must match
to maintain an orderly political system.
Otherwise, it's disorder and unrest.
I always say, "Don't be romantic about politics."
Politics has a high sense of reality, destiny,
and responsibility to the country.
Otherwise, you should not govern.
So many people are deceived by the westerner discourse.
For example, democracy, we love democracy.
You have to be specific - what kind of democracy?
And then we can talk about it.
Is it the money-talk democracy like in the U.S.,
or something else? The West likes abstract concepts.
Abstract concepts are fine.
For example, people around the world love peace,
ask Americans if they are willing to
accept peace as a universal value?
America chooses to reserve the right to use weapons.
Chinese people say "Practice is the only criterion to examine the truth."
You can have many beautiful wishes,
but you have to have a practical method
that is in line with national conditions.
Otherwise, the beautiful wishes may become heavy prices to pay.
We say politics is a very serious topic.
It is also highly professional, which
requires practical ways to achieve,
instead of just romantic ambitions.
Different ideas can be discussed.
One last question. Welcome.
My question is how to help these Arab countries
through the "Belt and Road Initiative"?
How can we send our warmth continuously during their "winter"?
- Thank you.
How to help these countries through
the "Belt and Road Initiative".
Actually, they don't need to learn
our model of development.
There are many fundamental things.
Under the western colonization system,
a third-world country can obtain
democracy, a legal system, a constitutional government,
freedom of speech, multi-party competition,
and many other things.
Except for two things - infrastructure and industrialization.
These two are fundamental.
Even from the perspective of politics, politics cannot
be built without infrastructure and industrialization.
Through the "Belt and Road Initiative",
they benefited from China's assistance in
infrastructure and industrialization.
I have been to some areas along
the "Belt and Road Initiative",
and I saw populations who hadn't worked
for hundreds of years
started working in factories and earning salaries.
This is a great first step.
So I joked when I attended meetings overseas,
that you Americans are the Grim Reaper,
throwing bombs everywhere you go,
and we Chinese are "God of Wealth",
bringing fortune everywhere we go.
Though it is a joke, think about it: the U.S has started
more than 200 wars in history -
statistics may be different.
Some people say the U.S. has only 17 years without wars in history.
Somebody calculated that everyday, the U.S.
throws a more than 10 bombs onto the earth.
Bandeira, a Brazilian scholar, has counted
the U.S. killed more than 6 million people
after the Second World War.
What can such a country bring to others?
China doesn't want to promote its model.
We can go separate ways.
"Let all flowers bloom together."
However, all countries can be prosperous together
when equipped with infrastructure and industrial conditions.
We can build a mutually beneficial, win-win and
complementary global economy.
That's what our leaders said,
"a community with a shared future for mankind".
I want to continue with the topic,
God of War and God of Wealth.
The U.S. started so many wars.
The newest story is a famous call
from Trump to Carter, ex-president in his 90s.
Trump asked, what do we do as China is taking us over?
Then Carter told thim that
over the past 40 years
China hasn't started any wars
while we have been in wars during the past 200 years.
That's why we are in this situation.
We can have the best infrastructure
if we invest one trillion.
However, we wasted three trillions to
wage wars, which is a huge mistake.
Actually, the development and
modernization of a country
essentially depends on its own people.
They need to find their own path.
This is the key.
China can offer some help on this.
Tianjin helped to build a development
park along the Suez Canal
and a glass fiber manufacturing
enterprise became pretty successful.
This enterprise received investment from Zhejiang and manufacturing takes place in the development park.
Now in terms of glass fiber,
China is the largest producer,
the U.S. is the second, and Egypt is the third,
only through this one enterprise.
It generates lots of jobs and pays taxes.
Nevertheless, for a large country with a
population of nearly 100 million,
issues cannot all be solved with even
10 projects like this.
Essentially, it relies on the country itself
to find the right path of development
based on its conditions of people and the country.
When I debated Fukuyama,
I said the reason it turned into an "Arab Winter"
is because the people's political awareness is not as high as China during Xinhai Revolution [which overthrew China's last imperial dynasty]
That's what I said.
Sometimes there is nothing they can do about it.
You have to try your luck, experience setbacks, and
eventually find the path to success.
Sometimes history is cruel.
The last question is what we can do.
And we talked about the Belt and Road Initiative,
which includes five links:
policy coordination, facility connectivity,
and the very important one,
people-to-people bonds.
These bonds are to truly understand, respect, and
acknowledge the people in an area and nation.
When we analyzed how the "Arab Spring"
turned into the "Arab Winter".
we don't just regarded it as a distant event,
but rather reflect on ourselves not to fall into this trap.
We need to see beyond that
and build our community with a shared future.
What else can we do and what more help
can we offer when we go forward together?
This might be our biggest inspiration.
Thanks to our two guests and everyone in the audience.
See you in our next episode.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 微信公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Preview of the next episode